<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lucia Darrow</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lucia Darrow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Outlier Detection with UCI Wines</title>
      <link>/post/outlier-detection-wines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/outlier-detection-wines/</guid>
      <description>The wine quality dataset is a classic machine learning dataset available on the UCI data archive. In this post, I’ll test a few approaches for outlier detection using the white vinho verde wine samples. These were provided by the Viticulture Commission of the Vinho Verde Region in Portugal in 2009.
Data ExplorationFirst let’s take a look at the structure of the data. There are 12 variables: 11 of these provide the results of physicochemical tests, while the quality field provides a rating for the wine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes an analytics project successful?</title>
      <link>/post/analytics-implementation-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/analytics-implementation-success/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is part of a series of posts on analytics change management.
Estimates of analytics project success rates are generally quite low. In 2019, a Gartner report predicted: &amp;ldquo;Through 2022, only 20% of analytic insights will deliver business outcomes&amp;rdquo; (White, 2019). More recent reports show continued struggle with implemenation of big data projects, citing problems with trust and integration (Henrion, 2019). In this series of blog posts, I&amp;rsquo;ll explore the key factors related to successful analytics project implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A/B Testing with Cookie Cats</title>
      <link>/post/a-b-testing-with-cookie-cats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-b-testing-with-cookie-cats/</guid>
      <description>About the gameCookie Cats is a colorful mobile game, where the user’s goal is to collect cookies (connect-4-style) and feed hungry cats. In this analysis, I use A/B testing to help decide at which level to place gates in the game. Gates are pauses in the game where the user must make an in-app purchase or wait a certain amount of time before progressing to the next level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing a Data-Centric Hackathon</title>
      <link>/post/organizing-a-data-centric-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/organizing-a-data-centric-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>Around this time last year, one of my co-organizers of the Vancouver chapter of RLadies brought forward the idea of hosting a data-centric hackathon. Many members of our group had participated in hackathons, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t have much experience in organizing an event of this scale. In addition, we knew we wanted our event to be a little different from other hackathons in that it would highlight data science projects and cater to participants of all skill levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle Cycling Trends</title>
      <link>/post/seattle-cycling-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/seattle-cycling-trends/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I revisit a bike and pedestrian traffic analysis I performed several months ago in light of the COVID-19 pandemic. The data supporting this analysis was sourced from the Seattle government transportation website and the original analysis was inspired by a R for Data Science Tidy Tuesday community event. I highly recommend checking out the Tidy Tuesday repository for fun, quick data challenges!
Seattle Bike Traffic OverviewFirst, let’s take a look at an overview of bike traffic over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Lucia Darrow is a Senior Operations Research Analyst with CANA Advisors, where she applies advanced analytics to commercial and government projects. Her specialties include mathematical representation, distillation of complex problems, and understanding user interaction requirements. Her research interests include implementation of analytics solutions and systems resilience.
Lucia is passionate about building community in analytics. She is a Junior Analyst Ambassador with the Military Operations Research Society, a co-organizer of RLadies Vancouver and the Co-Chair of the Vancouver Datajam.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
