<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lucia Darrow</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lucia Darrow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Organizing a Data-Centric Hackathon</title>
      <link>/post/organizing-a-data-centric-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/organizing-a-data-centric-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>Around this time last year, one of my co-organizers of the Vancouver chapter of RLadies brought forward the idea of hosting a data-centric hackathon. Many members of our group had participated in hackathons, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t have much experience in organizing an event of this scale. Little did we know, we&amp;rsquo;d be pivoting the event for online participation during a pandemic. In this post, I share a few lessons learned from organizing the Vancouver Datajam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle Cycling Trends</title>
      <link>/post/seattle-cycling-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/seattle-cycling-trends/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I revisit a bike and pedestrian traffic analysis I performed several months ago in light of the COVID-19 pandemic. The data supporting this analysis was sourced from the Seattle government transportation website and the original analysis was inspired by a R for Data Science Tidy Tuesday community event. I highly recommend checking out the Tidy Tuesday repository for fun, quick data challenges!
Seattle Bike Traffic OverviewFirst, let’s take a look at an overview of bike traffic over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ante mattis interdum dolor</title>
      <link>/post/post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Lucia Darrow is a Senior Operations Research Analyst with CANA Advisors, where she applies advanced analytics to commercial and government projects. Her specialties include mathematical representation, distillation of complex problems, and understanding user interaction requirements. Her research interests include implementation of analytics solutions and systems resilience.
Lucia is passionate about building community in analytics. She is a Junior Analyst Ambassador with the Military Operations Research Society, a co-organizer of RLadies Vancouver and the Co-Chair of the Vancouver Datajam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primis eget imperdiet lorem</title>
      <link>/post/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post1/</guid>
      <description>Example of post with missing date property.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
